[Music]
Let's meditate
Turn off your cell phones
[Music]
Think about Joe, think about the things you
have and how I
had the other life, I sent you those things: your
house, your possessions, your car, your family.
Then you're going to think about how you
got the things in this life
because I was very generous. He liked to
give things to others, he liked to
share.
[Music]
Close your
electronics.
And every day that you're
enjoying your city, your friends, your
electronics, your clothes, you're
using that karma, that debit card. [
Music]
[Music]
Concentrate for 5 minutes. Strive
to concentrate. Bring
back your breath.
[Music]
Slowly open your eyes.
Right. Second meditation. Let's go
directly to the second meditation.
What is it about?
What is the picture?
What is the meditation about? In that way,
all the little happinesses you've
always had, that came from keeping them,
from having kept those
good deeds. Ten virtues:
don't kill, don't steal, don't
mess with other people's partners, don't
lie.  It will
divide people, so
bad vibes with your language,
don't use useless language
that makes you envious and
upset when others have good things, do
n't rejoice when others are in
trouble even if you can't stand them,
and don't forget where the world comes from.
Every time you've done those ten,
excuse me, every time I do those ten, I
send some little happiness to the future
for you. I
live in, and well, it's
the biggest city in the world,
Mexico City, the second largest, and Rimbrook, I think,
is the third. I think there are
three thousand people.
We have a post office
in a restaurant,
two women who have been working there for about 100 years. You
write them a letter,
let's say you send yourself a letter, you seal it,
and they're
in a bag,
and it's like half a kilometer, a
little more, to their house,
like six days.
After six days,
the mailman
gives me the letter I wrote to myself,
and I open it.
Who am I mad at? Him. I'm
mad at the mailman. You
go home, and your partner says, "
You're stupid."
[Music] He
's just receiving a letter
you wrote a few weeks ago.
The partner  Only the postman
is delivering your own karma.
So it's silly to get angry at
those two old ladies at the post office. They did
nothing to me.
You sent yourself the letter,
and you sent yourself all the happiness in your
life.
[Music]
Things have happiness inside
them,
like music.
There's some happiness in music,
or when you touch your partner,
like when you eat something like churros.
But who put the happiness inside
it?
Sometimes when you eat a churro, you get
sick.
Sometimes when you try to play music to
calm down, you get more nervous
instead.
That means that thing doesn't have enough
karma inside.
So all the happiness you have,
all the good things that happen to you,
I put it inside the food or inside
the music.
Second meditation
that I did to put that thing inside
that thing,
like coffee.
Sometimes it makes you happy, sometimes it makes you
nervous. They
are very experienced at meditating, so I do
n't have to tell them how to breathe
and the posture and everything.
What happiness I sent myself.
Breath
and stretch
meditation. Third meditation,
a new one.
[Music]
I sent Us Beauty. I sent us beauty.
Two kinds of beauty, I sent Whatever.
The beauty, the beauty you have in your
face, I
have blue eyes, I like them,
but I didn't do anything to get my blue eyes,
I gave them to myself.
We have pride, vanity.
Oh, I have blue eyes, I have good
teeth, I have a
good shape to my ear. You
did nothing to me, I
tell you that, that's how you were
born.
But you still feel alone. I'm very
great,
it's a gift for
[Music].
Are you consuming it or are you serving?
With it
[Music], are you
using it, burning that karma? Are
you using it to generate more karma,
to help more people?
I like that. Are you either a consumer or
a servant?
If I give you a healthy body
[Music],
help people, don't
just play with it. Don't
get more boyfriends,
you can choose
[Music]
what you do with what I tell you.
You have a choice.
If you decide to use it to get more
boyfriends,
you're a consumer
and you'll lose it
and you'll get old
[Music].
You'll lose all that.
If you serve with it, you
'll be more beautiful
[Music].
Very few people are more beautiful than
young people, it's
because they've spent their time serving
others, other people,
like yoga
[Music].
I tell you, good body for yoga
[Music] I
can do this. The other
is because I gave you that body.
If you serve with it, you
can do yoga for many years.
Your little sister, how old has she been standing on her
head without hands
[Music]?
It's because she's a very good person to
others, she
serves others.
Those inner beauties, there's
also outer beauty.
Who made this incredibly beautiful
place?
Who made the sky blue?
Who is it? Who made the beauty
you hear in the song of the bird
or the ocean? So
the beauty you hear, the beauty you
see.
The sky was blue when you were born, the
day you were born. You did nothing to me,
but it can turn dark black
if you're a consumer. If you
only use that karma,
one day you'll lose the blue sky
and there will be darkness,
and most people go down that
path.
So let's do a meditation. It's
about five very pleasant minutes.
What beauty I gave you in your body!
Everyone has fingers.
Not everyone is handsome like Stanley,
but I gave me
very useful fingers. We
can all be happy for our
fingers.
Think about the beauty you have
and the beauty in your world.
The sky of this world is very beautiful.
Many people don't see it.  We
are very fortunate. I did a very good
job
creating the beauty of your face, the strength
of your body, the blue sky. What did I do
to generate those things?
[Music]
I didn't get angry
when there was traffic in Mexico City.
I was okay.
When people say, "Ah, you're a
fool," it's
okay.
No, dinner wasn't ready on time,
and I said, "Ah, very well, I can do a
five-minute meditation."
[Music]
That karma generated all the beautiful things you
have. So are you going
to be as easygoing as Joe?
If you're more easygoing than me, I'll
download
the sky where you live. There will be incredible things. I'll
show you a picture outside your house. I'm going
to send it to you right now.
[Music]
If you're a servant,
you're a servant of someone who doesn't get
upset, who doesn't get
angry. The blue sky will get more
incredible. You'll
keep seeing what incredible things
happen in the sky.
But if you're a consumer,
last week the
whole sky
[Music] was
a beautiful pink color.
If you do better than if you are  Better than
me, you
're more patient than me,
everything will be more beautiful.
But if you're not,
bad weather,
faces, old face. Okay,
meditation, let's do a meditation
about beauty,
the beauty of your body
and the beauty around you.
Think about where they come from. There's
nothing that doesn't come from something.
[Music]
Nothing can songs.
It's a song from before many were born.
[Music] I
was talking about her boyfriend. She says
something good correctly.
I have beauty.
The sky is blue.
[Music]
From having done something good.
This meditation is very pleasant.
All the beauty in your life,
your partner, Ria's face, baby, your baby,
the daddy's baby.
All that came to you because you didn't get angry.
Go back to breathing.
After a 5-minute meditation,
always three silent breaths.
You can get out and stretch.
[Music]
The face.
I like this app because it
shows you the faces of everyone
meditating at that moment in the world.
[Music]
These five minutes there were like 500
people meditating. It's great.
Okay,
let's go to the book.
[Music]
of my Just Finister
People and
[Music]
To be born here.
We just finished the part where the
people in Amitabha's paradise were
praying to be born here,
while the people here pray to
be in Amitabha's paradise.
[Music]
[Music] It
was difficult to translate. Cachiki
means some people.
[Music]
They want jewels.
And they go to a very famous statue in the
middle of the Antibeth.
[Music]
It's a statue that I think is of
Maitreya.
[Music]
The knee of the statue. They say
this jewel that's inside the statue
[Music]
means that it grants you all your
wishes.
So they say if you touch the knee of
the statue, you
walk around the knee of the
statue,
if you say a prayer on the knee
you will get everything you want.
It's like the wall in Jerusalem or something.
If you pray on this wall
your wishes will be granted,
and people like to say their prayers at the
level of the knee of the statue.
Mambo,
but if you have this kind of jewel that
grants you all your wishes
[Music]
means whatever you
want, this jewel will give it to you.
[Music]
In Western mythology, we have
Aladdin's lamp.
And if you rub it, the
genie comes out.
Ginny
is a genie who is like a spirit
and grants you only three wishes.
There are a lot of jokes at my
high school that I can't tell you about, I can't tell you
later. I tell the guys
about some kids who wished for
things but didn't get what they wanted.
So if you have one of those
Aladdin's lamps that grant
wishes,
they're going to make a dictionary entry
with the word "difficult."
[Music]
In this case, it means "pillow," and
in other cases, "significant."
And this is the jawbone.
[Music]
The model for coffee meditation.
If you sleep on that million jewels
that grant all your wishes,
[Music]
but when you die, it wo
n't help you avoid going to hell.
[Music]
Things, other people,
and your whole life, if you sleep on a
pillow that has a million jewels
that grant all your wishes, it wo
n't help you.  to protect not even a
second after your death,
but
this equipment that I gave you, this Body and
this Mind, this body and mind
is much better than those jewels
[Music] it's
super precious,
much more precious.
People tell me
[Music] a
parachute,
don't risk it. This jewel
is a very precious jewel, you can't get, you wo
n't be able to get another one,
Panchito, don't waste it by going
bungee jumping. And John, I
heard that many people have hurt themselves badly
doing that kind of thing.
I tell you something much more valuable than
that jewel that grants wishes, because
asking a spirit to give you what you
want and a
masching, you have to be able to
imagine it.
If you sow seeds of karma
for beauty
[Music], you will
obtain much more beauty than you
can currently imagine.
If you depend on your own way of
wishing, you can imagine, you're not able to
imagine, you're
able to imagine what this body
can give you.
This body is much more precious, much
more precious.
You can become like Tara,
but no, you can't imagine it. Okay,
so you have  that take care of it
and in chewing gum
[Music]
because it's better, what's
better, a jewel that can
help you for a day or a jewel that
can help you for 100 years,
of course the second is better
and that is your body and your mind
[Music]
for this you have to know Milarepa
I will look for him. The most famous meditator
of Tibet,
beautiful
meditations, wrote a beautiful poem
about his meditations. What
gives us hope is that he
started doing his deepest retreats
when he was 50 years old,
they have time
and we believe that he became a
Buddha. He is Milarepa,
his name Milarepa means a
special cotton towel.
He had no clothes, he had no time to
buy them, he had like a diaper made of a
natural cotton towel
[Music]
and he ate some green thorns that
are called neto,
with a lot of protein, very good for you. He
had no money and he made a
soup from these thorns and lived on that
alone
[Music]
the body and mind that the
Milarepa show gave him is not different, it is the same
as  Yours that the self gave you,
he started with the same equipment. It
took him a long time to start, until he
was 5 years old,
and then he became a Buddha.
But the equipment, the means he had
are the same as what you have
now. There's
nothing about his body and mind
that was better than yours.
Who saw the Lord of the Rings, the
third movie?
Smart, there's a dragon called Smoke,
a great and powerful dragon
who sleeps on a billion dollars' worth of
gold.
[Music]
More Smart, and here he's talking about
[Music]. It
means
treasure.
In yoga, we have panchacocha,
the five layers of our being. It means
cossio.
[Music]
All the treasure of the dragon. [
Music] Do
n't confuse it with pan, which means the
population of a country. I
already showed you all the bars.
[Music] It
's different.
And these dragons, the treasure they guard,
are pure jewels that grant wishes.
And they also have a jewel on the top of their
head, a special jewel.
This was the one Frodo wanted to have in the
movie.
[Music]
In the movie.
Can those jewels help the king
of the  Dragons becoming a
Buddha, no, no,
and nowadays they're like investment funds.
Ah, I have a 30 billion dollar investment fund.
I used to work with the Soros family.
His father, George Soros,
in England
[Music]
made a billion dollars in a single
day.
He had so much money that if he sold
all his money in pounds
sterling, he could ruin the
English economy in a single day,
and he did.
He bet that the pound
sterling would fall by two percent,
and he purposely
manipulated that so the currency would fall,
and in a single day, a billion dollars
went from England's money into his
pocket.
He's like that dragon. He
has all this money,
but he can't turn it into a Buddha. And I say,
your body and your mind are much more
valuable than all of George Soros's money.
You are much more powerful than Josh. You
have a body and a mind that
can become Buddhas.
[Music] It does
n't need to be said. Those
are words that mean... It doesn't
need to be said.
Not only those jewels are not capable of
helping the dragon become a
Buddha.
[Music]
Nor can he close the gates to
the lower realms five minutes
after the dragon's death.
The karma of stealing a billion
dollars from every person in England.
That money.
[Music]
That money can't protect you. Five minutes
after his death, he's going to be gone. He ca
n't protect you,
but your mind can. Your body can.
Your five-minute meditations
can protect you. Love
is much more valuable than a billion
dollars. Okay, you guys are rich,
super rich. It
would be really nice to have both.
Because if you have more money, you can
help more people. Okay,
that's a Tibetan breakfast.
I like it. The
monks use it a lot.
You take wheat
and toast it.
And we have parties where we
roast it
like a big griddle where you burn it
with two handles on the sides.
One person holds one handle and the other holds the
other,
and it's a big fire outside
at night,
and you start rocking the wheat like that.
And there are songs to do that,
and it's an all-night party.
[Music]
And then you put it in the blender in the
morning.
[Music]
And everyone, everyone...  Monks have a little
pouch of Tampa
that they tie to their belt
[Music]
and then I don't want to eat anymore. Ah, you don't
have to cook anymore
[Music]
when a monk eats, he just mixes it with
tea and eats it
[Music]
and then you go to debate or study, you do
n't have to waste time cooking anymore
and it has many nutrients,
it's a super fast food.
Not even a
milarepa, he didn't even have Samba work
and he was always without money and
from the blood,
but he Justin, but he used his equipment,
his means
[Music]
and he became a wedding in this life,
a Buddha in this life
[Music] there was
a great Yogi,
his name was Ame Chanchu Richen, he was
born in the year 2015
and died in the year 1077
and he had a student named
Chingaware. We
already told you a story before
Chingaware,
he had a student named
Tulunga
[Music]
he was making a big banquet
for all the monks in a house
and he was too busy to help
his Lama
and while he was cooking, the Lama's dog came in
and  Suddenly he understood something
[Music]
is much more important to me than
all the monks in this place.
Even my Lama's dog is much more
important than all the monks in this
place. And he
took the food and gave it to the dog
and received much better karma.
So we already have this Lama before, and
this
owner, the owner of the dog,
Lama said to him, "Hey, you're practicing
too hard. Relax, calm down a
little. Calm down.
Don't work so hard."
[Music]
And the student said, "I'm not worried."
[Music] "
I think I'm not generating enough
good karma to have this
opportunity again. I
respect that you ask me to
calm down a little,
but I'm afraid that I'm not
generating enough good karma to
have this opportunity again.
So I better try hard right now."
[Music] "I have to.
If you have this kind of
media equipment and you spend it, you
waste it just wanting to have fun
and just eating, just having, just
trying to have good
feelings."
[Music]
It's a story about a poor person,
a  A poor person rented a small,
very poor stone house.
You can see those kinds of houses in
India.
Someone just put some stones
together,
and this poor person rented the house.
[Music]
And one day, he saw a loose stone
and took it out
and found a large bag of gold.
[Music]
He put it in his bag on the
way to the city
to buy things,
and when he got to the city, he realized he
had lost the bag of gold.
iPhone 6. Like, Jessica, they
bought you an iPhone 6
and you put it in your bag.
[Music]
Well, in the morning you're very happy. Now
I have an iPhone 6. Before you can
text, you lose it,
Mom.
[Music]
How nice, how nice, they
give you a $900 iPhone 6 for
free. Before you can text, you loser.
And before you can send a message, you
lose it.
Before you send the first message,
in the old days
we said a bag of gold, now we say
an iPhone. He
couldn't spend a single penny of
that gold, which
means he lost it. He
left his  iPhone 6 at Starbucks and someone
else took it
[Music]
waste
or a great loss you
squandered it what are they talking about
squander waste your body and
mind
use it for great things
with your knees
[Music]
keep your precious mind here 10 minutes
at 10 in the morning
means third categories Why Every
Party is
going to summarize for you because every part of
your team is so precious
I want to add a few things
about how this team
is important for small goals
[Music]
like like having a good Renaissance
like becoming a Buddha
repa means cloth
which is a scripture cloth
means book
Pérez is scripture cloth
and we're doing a very good project
then I'm going to squeeze you in on that
we want to help the refugees in
Europe
one because they're fleeing from a
horrible war
and number two because a few
Muslims are killing people and
suddenly everyone hates Muslims all of them
So we have a project to
hire those refugees
to make cloths that wrap
scriptures
then I'll tell you
in the moment of danger
during  A war
or a crisis
when everyone is angry with the
Muslims
[Music]
and the Buddhists are like this.
We're going to help the Muslims, we're going to
love the Muslims
[Music]. I'm
going to give you some advice that isn't...
It's explained in the books
[Music]
Every day you
have to push,
strive. Don't waste a single day, don't
waste a single hour.
[Music]
The following meditation is
about enthusiasm
and fun
in Buddhism.
When we say push, strive, do
n't waste a single hour, we
don't mean being like, "
Okay, whining."
We mean having fun.
Okay.
Pushing and hard work in
Buddhism doesn't mean nervous
[Music]
and tired
[Music]. Have fun!
[Applause]
I'm going to have fun in yoga class.
Jump, I'm going to do it three times.
Hard Buddhist work
also means having fun
and taking care of yourself,
but don't waste your time.
This is advice from the mouth of one who is
n't from the book,
unfortunately. It's already in the book
too.
If you have an incense stick, light it.
Hello. How long does it take?
How long does it take to burn?
Like 5 minutes.
Don't waste even that amount
of time.
In the modern world, we can say the
time it takes to drink a coffee.
That's the measure.  Don't
waste more time than that.
You can waste 5 minutes,
10 minutes,
but no more.
Buddhist.
I want to see this in your hands. You
're not watching a video;
you're doing your 5-minute meditation. You already
have a tool. You
can use your enemy as a
tool.
This is the enemy of meditation.
You can climb the tiger.
Use your cell phone for your meditation.
Try to sow new, good seeds and
cleanse the old, bad seeds.
And in those five minutes, those little
moments of time that you save—two
artists—
those are the seeds that will
turn you into a Buddha. It's
not three years.
Excuse me, John, it's
not. The Three Minutes is not a
three-year meditation retreat.
[Music]
You can become enlightened using those
5-minute periods of time that
most people waste.
[Music]